国王陛下驾到
His majesty,the king.
我亲爱的妹妹
My dear sister.
祝你一路顺风
Fare you well on your journey.
记住 葡萄牙国王 你未来的丈夫
Remember the king of portugal, your future husband,
他爱你 尊敬你
loves and respects you.
你必须同样爱他
You must love him in return.
记住你的承诺 他死之后 我要嫁我中意的人
Remember your promise! When he dies, I marry whom I choose.
查尔斯
Charles.
如同你爱我般照顾好她
As you love me, take care of her.
我会 请您安心
I will. You may have no doubts.
我会视其为自己生妹
I shall treat her as if she were my own sister.
上帝与你们同在
God be with all of you!
牢记你们的职责
And remember your duties,
对我王妹 对英格兰的职责
to my lady and to england.
一同祈祷
Let us pray.
教皇感谢上帝赐予我们一位
His holiness thanked god for raising up such a prince
如此忠于礼教的王子
to be a champion of the church.
他震撼于您肯花时间撰写这本书册
He expressed astonishment that you'd found time to write the pamphlet.
另外 为了表示他的感谢
Furthermore,in order to show his gratitude
教皇决定给您冠上新头衔
the pope has decided to honour you with a new title:
护教者
Fidei defensor.
信念的守护者
Defender of the faith.
但陛下您需知晓 马丁-路德
But your majesty should know that martin luther
也对您的书册做出了回应
has also responded to your work.
他说什么了？
What did he say?
他谴责您是…
Well he accuses you of...
是什么？
yes?
他谴责您像个撒泼的妓女般咆哮
He accuses you of raving like a strumpet in a tantrum.
什么 ？
What!?
他说 若英格兰国王让他自己 能堂堂地滥吼谬误
He says if the king of england gives himself the right to spew out falsehoods,
那么他就能让我堂堂地 把谬误塞回他喉咙里
then he gives me the right to stuff
他该被烧死
He ought to be burned!
动手拉绳子
Give me a hand with these ropes!
这是您的特等舱
This is your stateroom.
希望得到殿下您的满意
I hope it meets with your highness's approval.
凑合
It'll serve.
床不宽 但够用
The bed is narrow but adequate.
没有大状况 这些板子不会移动
In the case of action all this
状况？
Action?
万一我们遭受袭击
If we are attacked.
谁会袭击我们？
Who will attack us?
海盗
Pirates.
在我看来 大人
It seems to me, your grace,
比起海盗 更需要我们提防的人已经在船上
we have more to fear from the pirates already onboard!
早安 夫人
Good morning,madam.
陛下
Your majesty.
Your majesty,
安… 克利福德女士来访
lady anne... clifford.
陛下
Your majesty.
(致国王陛下)
高贵的陛下
Your gracious majesty.
退还您相赠礼物 使我无比痛心
It causes me such pain and grief to return the gifts you gave
啊 如此精美饰物 岂我能相配…
Alas,they are too beautiful and I unworthy to receive them...
我应不曾让陛下有馈赠之理
I think I never gave your majesty cause to give them to me,
我如此微不足道 而您却如此举足轻重
since I am nothing and you are everything.
恳请您 将此华饰 赠予应得陛下宠幸之人
Give them,I pray you, to a lady more deserving of your majesty's affections.
我正离宫前往西弗的家中
I am leaving now for my family's house at hever.
我会一路挂念着您
I shall think of you on the journey there.
您忠实的仆人
Your loving servant,
安-博林
anne boleyn.
伦敦塔
TOWER OF LONDON
佩斯先生
Mr. Pace.
有何能为您效劳 先生
At your service,sir.
您被释放了
You are to be released.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
什么意思？我说您被释放了
What's that? I said,you're to be released.
我告诉过妻子
I told my wife.
我说 我不知道 什么都不知道
I said: I don't know anything. Anything at all.
您告诉过您妻子 佩斯先生？什么时候？
You,told your wife, mr. Pace? When?
嘘…
Shh...
她睡着了
she's sleeping.
我们谈天
We talk together.
我以为她死于儿子的难产
I thought she had died when she gave birth to our son.
我肯定我…
I was sure I...
我去了葬礼 还哭了
I went to the funeral,and wept.
可现在…
But now...
我看见她如同我一般
I see she's alive
依旧存活在这个世界里
and as well as I.
你看不到她？
Do you not see her?
看到 佩斯先生 我能看到她
Yes,mr. Pace. I see her.
克伦威尔先生
Mr. Cromwell!
阁下
Eminence.
我注意到你很久了
I have long noticed your
你工作上天资聪颖 落实我交办之事也十分勤奋
aptitude for work and your diligence in carrying through my affairs.
还有你的判断力
And your discretion.
感谢阁下如此器重
I am grateful to your eminence.
你出身低微
You are of obscure stock.
与我一样
But then so am I.
但这不足以成为你的牵绊
It should not be held against you.
我手上可能有份适合你的职务
I may have a proposition to put to you.
谢谢 主教阁下
Thank you,your eminence.
根据我国与罗马皇帝的协议条款
By the terms of our treaty with the emperor,
我们有责任为他提供战争经济援助
we are obliged to support his war effort financially.
目前他的军队在意大利和法军交战
At present his armies are fighting the french in italy.
米兰附近
Near milan.
不幸的是 我计算过 为了达成我方义务
Unfortunately,I have calculated that in order to meet our obligations
只能提高税收
we shall be obliged to raise taxes.
赠税议案将在下次议会上提出
A bill will be presented to parliament at the next session.
好 行
Good. Good.
我有信心 议案会顺利通过的
I trust the bill will pass successfully.
我确信 一切都尽在主教大人您的掌握中
I'm sure,your eminence,with your guiding hand it will be so.
至少 我们和罗马皇帝的联盟 受到如此的拥戴
At least our alliance with the emperor is popular.
尽管有时我自问 为何会如此呢？
Although I sometimes ask myself, why that should be so?
因为他不是法国人
Because he's not french!
确实
Right.
新战舰已经委托给朴次茅斯港铸造
The new warship is commissioned at portsmouth.
嗯
Mm hm.
忘了跟您说
I forgot to mention to your majesty.
宫中新来一位访客 纳瓦拉的玛格丽特公主
We have a new visitor at court, princess marguerrite of navarre.
昨日我亲自接待的她 是位十分美丽的年轻少妇
I received her myself yesterday. I found her a very beautiful young woman,
脾性甜美而顺从
with a very sweet, and yielding,disposition.
她表明了对陛下您的仰慕
She confessed a great admiration for your majesty.
是否要安排…
Should I arrange...?
是 是的 安排吧
Yes. Yes do it!
陛下已经应允我的 我想要指派一位新秘书
With your majesty's permission, I intend to appoint a new secretary,
代替佩斯先生
instead of mr. Pace.
行
Yes!
咱们到里斯本寻欢作乐吧 兄弟们
We're gonna have fun in lisbon,boys!
那儿的妓女可是全世界最棒的
The whores are the best in the world.
就算她们说的你一个字都不懂
Even if you can't understand a word they say.
她们不跟我说话的
They don't talk to me.
她们嘴里都满着呢
They always have their mouths full!
你看看 大人 我的王压了你的后 (扑克牌的K和Q)
There you are,your grace. My king has your queen.
我比较希望压王后的是小鬼
Well,I was rather hoping that the knave would get the queen.
阁下
Eminence.
陛下
Your majesty.
允许我介绍纳瓦拉的玛格丽特公主
May I present princess marguerrite of navarre.
夫人
Madame.
陛下
Majeste.
你是来做客的？
You are visiting here?
是的陛下 伯爵… 我丈夫
Oui,majeste. The count,my husband,
有事留在法国无法同来 很遗憾
had to stay behind in france,regrettably.
的确 非常遗憾 夫人
Indeed. Very regrettable,madame.
你会得到补偿的
But you must be compensated.
在这里你一定会享受到乐趣
You must enjoy some pleasures whilst here.
我有个消息 大人也许会感兴趣
I have some news, which may interest your grace.
温彻斯特的主教6个月前逝世
The bishop of winchester died 6 months ago.
嗯
Mm hm.
温彻斯特是英格兰最富有的教区
Winchester is the richest parish in england.
沃尔西本该委任其继任人
Wolsey is supposed to appoint his successor.
而且他已经提出任命者
And he just did.
就是他自己
He appointed himself.
那男人到底想要多少财富？
How much more wealth does that man want?
- 还有更多 - 告诉我
-  There's more. -  Tell me!
似乎他正用国王的部分钱财
It appears that he's been using some of the king's money
为他在牛津的新学院投资
to invest his new college in oxford,
还有他私人的基金
and his own personal foundation.
他关闭最不景气的修道院 剥夺它们全部资产
He closes down the worst monasteries, strips them of their assets,
这么做是应该的
as he is supposed to do
但这些收益 并没有流入国王的小金库
but instead of transferring all the profit to the privy purse
而是全部不见了
he makes all the profits disappear.
上帝 你必须告知国王 马上
God. You must tell the king. Right away.
请原谅 大人
Forgive me,your grace,
但我们得审时度势
but we must judge the time,exactly.
沃尔西已是国王心腹 无论证据
Such is wolsey's hold over the king that
如何不利于他 国王都不会相信
whatever the evidence against him,the king won't believe it.
但总会有时机出现
But there will come a point.
当国王对这位大臣的信任 悬置未决的时候 大人
When the king's belief in his minister will hang in the balance and then,your grace
我们就能把真相抖落到天平上
we shall drop our truth into the scales
天平就会倾斜
and the scales will fall.
亲爱的托马斯
Dear thomas!
陛下
Majesty.
留在宫里 我需要你
Come and stay at court. I need you.
我给你华丽的住所
I'll give you great chambers.
康普顿的住所很好的 给你用
Compton has great chambers. You can have his!
如同我爱陛下您一般 我希望住所中能有我的家人
Much as I love your majesty, I like my chambers to have my family inside them.
当然
Indeed.
国王陛下钟爱你胜过任何人 摩尔先生 您知道的
His majesty loves you above anyone else, mr. More,you know that.
也许如此
That may be true.
但 若我的人头 能为他换来西班牙的一座城堡
And yet,if my head were to win him a castle in spain,
我想他会砍下来的
I think he would cut it off.
怀亚特先生
Mr. Wyatt.
陛下
Your majesty.
听说你是位诗人
I hear you're a poet.
噢 我写诗 但不知道算不算诗人
Oh. I write poems. I don't know how to be "a poet. "
我略有欣赏 很得我欢欣
I've read some. I like them.
陛下 我感激无言
My lord,I don't know what to say.
你爱着安-博林？
Were you in love with anne boleyn?
我…
I...
沃尔西主教告诉我 你们曾有婚约
cardinal wolsey tells me you were once engaged.
不 并非如此
No! That's not true.
你爱过她？
Did you love her?
安女士如此美丽 任何男人都有责任爱她
Lady anne is so beautiful it is the duty of every man to love her.
我当然爱过她 但只是暗恋
Of course I loved her but from a distance.
而我本人是有妇之夫
Personally,I have a wife.
吃好喝好
Enjoy the feast.
托马斯？托马斯-塔利斯
Thomas? Thomas tallis!
您好
Hello.
我们只想说 我们爱你的音乐
We just wanted to say we love your music.
谢谢
Thank you.
我俩同房 你想跟我们回去吗？
We share a room. Do you want to come back with us?
我想把这首曲子作完
I want to finish this song.
明天再写
But finish it tomorrow.
明天就会忘掉
I'll have forgotten it by tomorrow.
你也会忘掉我们
And you'll forget us,too.
康普顿 我的朋友
Compton,my friend,
觉得纳瓦拉的玛格丽特公主如何？
what do you think of princess marguerrite de navarre?
天生尤物 陛下
She's well built your majesty.
不过照我的喜好 上围稍重了些
Little heavy in the top decks for my taste though.
她是弗朗西斯的妹妹
She's francis' sister.
碰巧让我知道
I happen to know that.
嗯哼…
Mm hm...
噢 陛下
oh,majeste.
啊 陛下
Ah,majeste.
喔 啊
Ouu,ahh.
- 哦 我的天 亨利 - 我的天
-  Ah,mon dieu,henri. -  Mon dieu,
亨利
henri.
完事
C'est fini.
何时何地我都乐意赢你的钱
Happy to take your money anytime or place.
船长 你该省点钱到里斯本用
You should save your money captain, for when we get to lisbon.
晚安
Good night.
让路
Out of the way.
让开 让开
Make way. Make way.
罗马皇帝的信史到 陛下
A messenger from the emperor, your majesty.
怎么了？出什么事了？
Well?! What is it?
皇帝陛下大胜法军
The emperor has won a great victory against the french.
你的意思是？
What are you saying?
五天前 在帕维亚战役大获全胜
At the battle of pavia, 5 days ago,
皇帝的军队完全占据上风
the emperor's army totally overcame those of the french.
法军已溃不成军
The french army was destroyed.
上帝
My god!
所言属实？
Is this true?!
不止如此 法兰西国王本身 亦在战场就擒
Not only that! The french king himself was also captured on the battlefield.
弗朗西斯？
Francis?
弗朗西斯国王被擒？
King francis was captured?!
是的 陛下
Yes,your majesty.
他现为皇帝的阶下囚
He's now the emperor's prisoner.
你的到来好比天使长加百列降临
You are as welcome here as the angel gabriel.
去吃饱吧
Feed yourself!
喜讯到来 庆祝
Great news! We must celebrate!
上啊
Come!
攻击
Attack!
安东尼-耐弗特先生得分
Point to mr. Anthony knivert!
干得好 托尼
Well done,tony!
告诉你 威廉 我今天一定会被加封骑士
I tell you,william. I will be called a knight today,
不然就永远不会了
or I never will be.
国王陛下迎战
His majesty,the king.
我的王后
My queen.
我的王
My lord.
- 为国王陛下欢呼 - 夫人
-  Hoorah for his majesty! -  My lady.
祝您胜利 陛下
Godspeed,your majesty!
你也看到皇后多么受人爱戴
You see how popular the queen is with the people.
她是易莎贝拉和费德南的女儿
She is the daughter of isabela and ferdinand.
或许人们认为皇后就该像她这样
Perhaps the people think she is what a queen ought to be.
威廉-康普顿先生接受陛下的挑战
Mr. William compton takes his majesty's challenge!
您今天看来有些许不悦
You seem out of sorts today.
我自有沮丧和痛苦的理由
I have reasons to be downcast and pained.
但那些沮丧和痛苦并不让你困扰
But they needn't bother you.
为什么我们不该承受痛苦？
Why should we not have pains?
有些人认为我们该享受于天堂的羽绒暖床
Some people think we ought to go to heaven in feather beds!
但是不该那样
But that is not the way.
我们的主升天时被痛苦和磨难缠身
The lord himself went there in pain and tribulation.
当然 我并不是说您是那样…
Not that I'm suggesting that you're like that. Of course.
您准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
我生来就已准备好 威廉
I was born ready william.
进攻得分 国王陛下得分
Attack! A point for his majesty the king!
不要看我
Do not look at me.
我请求你私下替我做件事
I ask you privately to do something for me.
将这封信带给皇帝殿下
Take this letter to the emperor.
你能替我完成这件任务吗？
You will do this for me
不得将此信给他人看 也不得同他人提及只言半语
and not show it to anyone nor speak a word about it.
再一局
Again!
进攻得分 国王陛下赢得两分
Attack! Two points for his majesty.
"你不肯接受这些珠宝让我暗自忧伤"
"I was distressed you would not accept the brooches.
"这些珠宝并非为她人 而专门为你而铸"
They were made for you, not for anyone else.
"为何我视你如珍宝 你却自认渺小"
And why are you not worthy when I deem you so?
"对汝芳心的渴望… "
For certain,it must be plain to you
"在你看来一定微不足道"
now that I desire to find a place in your heart."
等等 给我
wait! Give it to me!
给我
Give it.
对汝芳心的渴望
Desire to find a place in your heart
以及对你深爱的向往
and your grounded affection.
深爱？
Grounded affection?
深爱
Grounded.
跟我说你们私下见过面
Tell me at least that we can meet in private.
"能够与你倾心比什么都重要"
I mean nothing more than a chance to talk to you.
"我恳求你 快速回宫"
I beg you, come back to court soon.
快点还给我 哥哥
Come... give it back,brother.
与此同时
And meanwhile
看在上帝的份上 请接受这份礼物 并让其有幸被佩戴
accept this new gift and wear it,for my sake.
什么礼物 在哪儿？
What gift? And where is it?
哦 老天爷
Oh holy jesus!
拿过来 小伙子们
Bring it here,lads.
你什么时候带我的外甥女回宫？
When will you bring my niece back to court?
我看就快了
Soon,I think.
现在 国王的胃口被吊起来
Now the king's appetite is whetted.
这是什么？
What's this?
小把戏而已 陛下
Just a trick,your majesty.
小把戏而已
Just a trick.
国王陛下 对战 安东尼-耐弗特先生
His majesty,the king and mr. Anthony knivert!
- 长枪 - 就绪
- Lance. - A plaisance!
准备好了吗
Ready?!
长枪
Lance.
冲
Yeah!
国王忘记扣下面罩
The king's forgotten his visor.
坚持住 坚持住 国王陛下
Hold! Hold! Hold! The king! The king! Hold!
陛下 陛下
Majesty! Your majesty!
- 我没受伤 - 让我看看
- I'm not hurt! - Let me see.
- 没有伤到眼睛 感谢上帝 - 给我一块手帕
- It's not your eyes,thank god. -  A cloth to me!
好了
Okay.
看 看到了吗？
See! See?!
陛下
Majesty!
您能原谅我吗？您能原谅我吗？
Will you forgive me? Will you?
那不是你的错 安东尼 不是你的错
It's not your fault anthony! It's all my fault!
是我的错 你伤不到我
It's my fault! You didn't hurt me.
- 你伤不到我 - 我不能
- You can't hurt me. -  No!
再战一局
Try it again!
亨利 亨利
Henry. Henry.
夫人 不要惊慌
Madam, have no fear.
我要再次跨上战马 证明给这里所有的人看
I intend to ride again and prove to everyone here
我刀枪不入
that I'm well and unharmed.
如果您坚持… 但我宁愿您改变主意
If you insist,but I would much rather you did not.
夫人
My lady.
戴好盔甲
Arm yourself!
遵命
Yes.
准备迎接我的挑战吗 安东尼？
Are you ready for me anthony?
英格兰人民 你们的国王平安无事
People of england, your king is unharmed!
长枪
Lance!
有呼吸吗？
Is he breathing?
叫医生
Get a physic!
耐弗特
Knivert!
安东尼 安东尼
Anthony! Anthony.
您召见我 殿下？
You want to see me, your highness?
只是问问还得在海上多久？
Only to ask how much longer we must be at sea?
顺风的话 再两天
With a fair wind,2 more days.
你玩牌吗 大人？
Do you play cards,your grace?
有时… 殿下
Sometimes... your highness.
我们玩什么好？
What game shall we play?
悉听尊便
You choose.
法式出王牌
French ruff.
你来抽王
You pick trumps.
国王(扑克牌的K)
Kings.
手气好而已 殿下
How appropriate your highness.
要酒吗？
Wine?
随您意
As you please.
殿下对您的婚礼一定很期待吧？
Your highness must be looking forward with great anticipation to your wedding?
我听说对方国王骑术了得…
I hear the king was a great horseman...
在他在位时期 还因美丽的情人们著名
in his time. And famous for his beautiful mistresses.
不要揶揄我 我不喜欢
Don't tease me. I don't like it.
一个老男人试图跟您做爱时 您喜欢吗？
Will you like it when an old man tries to make love to you?
大人这话说太过了 已经
Your grace goes too far. Already.
福音书说 真相让人自由
Gospel says the truth will make you free.
现在你渎神了
Now you are blasphemous!
我可怜的女士们不该听到你的言语
My poor ladies should not hear you!
夫人
My lady.
- 夫人 - 夫人
-  My lady. -  My lady.
我要你离开
I want you to leave.
是吗？
Do you?
对 现在
Yes. Now.
遗憾
Pity.
我手气正好
I had a winning hand.
给皇帝传信
Send a message to the emperor.
告诉他我们对他在帕维亚的大胜 还有法兰西国王擒住
Tell him of our joy and contentment at his great victory at pavia,
是多么喜悦和欢欣
and his capture of the french king.
是 陛下
Yes,your majesty.
问他准备如何处置弗朗西斯
Ask him what he intends to do with francis.
还有既然俘虏了弗朗西斯
And whether or not, with francis captive,
是否现在 并非攻打法国本土的好时机？
it may not be a good time to think about striking france itself?
告诉他我们有黄金 人力和战船 任之利用
Tell him we have gold, men and ships at his disposal,
我们急切希望参战 共享他的荣誉
and are eager to do battle and share some of his glory.
谨遵吩咐
Yes,I shall.
啊 陛下 这位是您的新秘书
Ah! Your majesty. This is your new secretary.
托马斯-克伦威尔 训练有素的律师 勤勉的人 一位学者
This is thomas cromwell. He is a trained barrister, a diligent man and a scholar.
他将会对陛下您效力非凡
I think he'll be very useful for your majesty.
- 克伦威尔先生 - 陛下
- Mr. Cromwell. - Majesty.
女士们
Ladies.
你回宫了
You're back at court.
私下见面好吗？
May I see you privately?
甜心
Sweetheart.
父王 父王
Le roi! Le roi!
您好吗？
How are you?
很好 我的小东西 你呢？
Good, my little baby. How about you?
还不错啦
Not bad.
夫人
My lady.
沃尔西为什么拆我的信？
Why does wolsey open my letters?
我难道不是英格兰的王后？
Am I not the queen of england?
- 你确定他拆了？ - 确定
-  You sure he does? -  I am sure.
那么我会阻止他的
Then I shall stop it.
沃尔西主教有时热心过头
Cardinal wolsey can be too zealous.
但永远都在为我们的利益效力
But it is always in our interest.
除非你藏了什么秘密
Unless you have secrets!
安东尼-耐弗特先生到
Mr. Anthony knivert.
安东尼
Anthony.
陛下
Majesty.
你差点儿瞎了一只眼睛
You almost lost an eye.
反正那只也不太用
Never use that one much anyway.
跪
Kneel.
我封你为安东尼-耐弗特爵士
I dub thee sir anthony knivert.
请起 安东尼爵士 接受公证
Arise sir anthony and be recognized.
威廉·康普顿先生
Mr. William compton.
这责难的眼神是为什么 安东尼爵士？
Why so reproving a look,sir anthony?
陛下 我为同样的称誉 几乎失去一只眼睛
Your majesty,I nearly lost an eye for the same report.
啊 可你没有搬过树
Ah! But you never carried a tree.
威廉
William!
跪
Kneel.
因此 我们都要清楚 那个教皇
So that is why it is to be understood that the pope,
没资格算圣彼得的后裔
far from being a descendant of st. Peter,
他是个罪人 伪君子 是恶魔忠心的奴仆
is a sinner,a hypocrite, a handmaiden to the devil,
说到底 是活生生的反基督者
and the living anti-christ on earth!
这就是路德教导我们的
This is what luther teaches us,
为了让我们从错误的崇拜 和虚假的神灵中脱身
in order to free us from false worship and false idols.
为了让我们回归真正的宗教
In order that we might return to the true religion
走上结满真理果实的道路 直达救赎
and take the true and fruitful path to salvation!
我们的讯息 关于希望
Our message of hope,
关于自由 关于真理 已经在欧洲蔓延开来
of liberty,of truth is already spreading throughout europe,
传遍每个角落
from one corner to the other.
在这里 在英格兰
Here in england,
我们已撒下一粒种子
we have planted a seed
它将会 伴随祈祷 伴随行动
that will, with prayer,with action,
或许还伴随牺牲
and perhaps even with sacrifice,
总有一天长成参天大树
grow one day to become a great tree
它的枝条将覆盖整个王国
whose branches will over-reach the kingdom
摧毁所有反基督的腐烂的修道院
and destroy the putrid monastic houses of the anti-christ!
而这棵树…
And this tree...
这棵树将被命名自由之树
this tree will be called the liberty tree.
我主之天使将在其枝头歌唱…
And in its branches all the angels of the lord will sing...
- 哈利路亚 - 哈利路亚
-  hallelujah. -  Hallelujah.
哈利路亚
Hallelujah.
我梦想这一刻很久了
I have dreamt of this moment a long time.
安
Anne,
你要知道 我整颗心都渴望着你
you must know I desire you with all my heart.
刚才跟你调情的年轻男子
The young man you were dallying with earlier?
他是谁？
Who was he?
我哥哥乔治
My brother george.
王后陛下在等我
Her majesty expects me.
再会
Later.
那是谁 陛下？
Who was that, your majesty?
一个女孩
Just a girl.
您的新王国
Your new kingdom.
国王一定很期待…
The king must be looking forward...
别 不许说
don't! I forbid you.
我本该恨你
I should hate you.
但你不恨
But you don'T.
我知道你不恨
I know you don'T.
我该怎么办？
What will I do?
里斯本皇宫
ROYAL PALACE LISBON
救我
Save me.
玛格丽特…
Margaret...
你比画像上更漂亮
YOU ARE EVEN MORE HANDSOME THAN YOUR PORTRAIT.
我太幸运了
I FEEL SO GREATLY FORTUNATE,
你即将成为我的王后
THAT YOU ARE SOON TO BE MY QUEEN.
这里的一切都是你的
EVERTHING HERE IS AT YOUR DISPOSAL.
我只要你开心就好
I ONLY WANT YOU TO BE HAPPY.
还有让我开心就好
AND TO MAKE ME HAPPY.
然后在上帝的帮助下
AND THEN WE WILL MAKE CHILDREN,
我们会生很多孩子
MANY CHILDREN...
子女满堂
WITH GODS HELP!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
执行国王的吩咐
What the king ordered!
也许你不明白
Perhaps you don't understand.
但我无法入眠
But I can't sleep,
单单想到你 我便无法呼吸
I can hardly breathe, for thinking of you.
每个醒着的时刻 你的样子总浮现我眼前
Your image is before my eyes every waking second.
我几乎要相信 自己会牺牲掉我的王国
I almost believe that I would
只求在你怀中一小时…
for an hour in your arms...
请求你
I beg you,
给我一个能见面的地点 时间
name some place that we can meet,and when
让我证明我对你的真爱 是超越一般爱情的挚爱
where I can show you truly an affection which is beyond a common affection.
你的仆人 亨利 亲笔
Written with the hand of your servant,henry.
现在他成了你的仆人
Now he is your servant.
加上些微妙关心和你肉体的诱惑
With some subtle care and the lure of your flesh,
他能成为更亲近的人
he may become something even closer.
阿门
Amen.
陛下是否…
Did his majesty...?
留步
Hold!
怎么了？
What is it?
沼泽太宽 我们得绕道而行
Ground's too boggy. We're gonna have to go around.
谁说的？
Says who?
我们跳不过这道沟的 陛下
We can't jump this ditch,your majesty.
是你们跳不过这道沟
You mean you can't jump this ditch.
旗杆
Flag pole!
陛下？
Majesty?
嗯 安东尼爵士？
Yes,sir anthony?
您要做什么？
What are you doing?
我要跨越这条蠢沟
I'm going to vault this stupid ditch.
没有任何东西能成为我和我矫健之躯的阻扰
Nothing stands in the way of me and my sport.
您确定？
Are you sure?
给你们看看英格兰国王的能耐
Just watch and see what the king of england can do.
噢
Oh!
陛下
Your majesty!
找医生来 快
Fetch a physician! Quickly!
如蒙陛下恩准
With your majesty's permission,
我可否与您妻子共舞一曲？
may I dance with your wife?
你什么时候走？
When do you leave?
明天
Tomorrow.
不行
You can'T.
为什么不行？
Why can't I?
我已功成圆满
I've discharged my duty.
我为什么要留下？你还有你的日子要过
Why should I stay? You have a life to lead.
真奇怪
It's strange.
有些人看上去健康无比
Some men who seem at the peak of health,
正值青年 充满活力 却突然倒下死亡
who still are young and full of life suddenly collapse and die.
同样奇怪的 有些老人
By that same counter, some old men,
看上去身体已经老旧 了无生气…
whose bodies look worn out, whose race seems run...
他们还能撑上几年呢
they can go on for years.
不觉得奇怪吗？
Don't you think it's strange?
你这样奚落我 是因为好玩？
Do you tease me because it amuses you?
不然为什么？
Why else?
因为你爱我
Because you love me.
陛下
Your majesty.
我们要给您放血 就放少许
We would like to bleed you,a little.
让那些使您痛苦不堪的胆汁流走
To drain away the bile which is causing your majesty so much pain.
您是否允许？
With your permission?
准
Yes.
我差点死了
I almost died.
是 陛下
Yes,your majesty.
去你的"是 陛下" 我差点死了 听不懂啊？
No not "yes,your majesty. " I almost died! Don't you understand?
从那刻起 我想了很多
Since that moment,I've done a great deal of thinking.
万一我真的死了怎么办？
What if I had died?
我都留下什么？
What would I have left?
我没有子嗣 只有一个女儿 和一个杂种儿子
I have no heir only a daughter and a bastard son.
明白吗 沃尔西？
You understand,wolsey?
都铎王朝… 完了
The tudor dynasty... gone!
我父王的成就 全完了 且是因为我的错
All my father's work,finished! And it's my fault.
我过了太久享乐的日子
I have lived too long for pleasure.
从来未打算过未来
I never even thought of the future!
我娶了亡兄的妻子 上帝已经惩罚了我
I married my brother's wife and god has punished me!
我如此愚蠢
I've been such a fool.
现在一切都变了
Now everything has changed.
一切
Everything.
我要离婚
I want a divorce.
你来筹备一切
And you will get one for me.